#### SHARON CLAUDETTE SMITH

1512 Millhous Drive Cary, NC 27513 919-208-5998 sharonclaudettesmith@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Multi talented professional with 16 years of progressive experience with emphasis in accounts receivable/payable, billing, account reconciliation, sales, data entry, and customer service. A top performer who is well organized, detail-oriented and possesses excellent analytical and problem solving skills. Easily adapts to ever changing environments and challenges.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Randstad Professionals @ Wells Fargo Corporate, Raleigh, NC Bankruptcy Specialist

07/2015 - 10/2015

- Monitored the overall process of bankruptcy from referral to disposition.
- Maintained timely and accurate completion of processes which encompassed set-up upon notification, preparation of Proof of Claim, Motion for Relief of Stay, pursuit of Reaffirmation Agreement, monitored Plan Payment Review performances and case dismissal or discharge.
- Used Outlook for internal and external communication, maintaining calendars and schedules.
- Communicated with legal counsel and investors to determine best practices for mitigating losses.
- Completed research, analyzed results and responded to bankruptcy related inquiries made by debtor's Counsel
  or Trustees.

# Manpower @ Seterus/IBM, RTP, NC Bankruptcy Specialist I

03/2015 - 07/2015

- Monitored various aspects of the Bankruptcy process including payment changes, payoffs and loan set ups.
- Reviewed and reconciled suspense reports and payment processing.
- Reviewed and updated MSP with bankruptcy information.
- Worked internal MSP tracking queues and removed files from bankruptcy as necessary.

# **Aerotek** @ Wells Fargo Corporate, Raleigh, NC *Operations Analyst 2* — Three month contract assignment

12/2013 - 03/2014

- Financial Fitness Team support staff in the review process of hiring Mortgage Loan Originators.
- Reviewed applicant credit reports for delinquent trade line accounts, judgments, bankruptcies and liens.
- Prepared credit reports for reviewers to analyze.
- Initiated emails to applicants for a response to the derogatory items on credit report.
- QC of outgoing initial credit report requests created by Wells Fargo, India.
- Data entry and QC of various Excel reports.

### HP Enterprise Services, Raleigh, NC Senior A/R Cash Analyst/Trainer, NC Medicaid

08/2008 - 06/2013

- Researched and keyed NC Medicaid refunds received from lockbox into MMIS.
- Processed all company checks, stale dated, escheated funds and Electronic Funds Transfer rejects.
- Communicated to providers with outstanding checks to identify when an escheatment was owed.
- Researched and determined if checks met criteria for escheatment to disperse to the state.
- Exported files in Excel format for processing payments.
- Researched, resolved and reconciled billing discrepancies as well as created billing reports.
- Performed Accounts Receivable functions using internal Oracle financial system.
- Primary trainer for permanent and contract employees for the cash team.

- Serviced accounts for Mortgage Lenders resolving inquiries and complaints regarding PMI.
- Bank of America was largest customer.
- Researched and reconciled billing including over/under payments, cancelled loans.
- Processed Partial land releases, and West Virginia and Kentucky tax issues.
- Processed wire transfers, ran portfolio audits.
- Created Excel spreadsheet to track and document client information.
- Prepared monthly billing statements.
- Wrote Policy Servicing procedure manuals.

#### GE Mortgage Insurance, Raleigh, NC

05/1997-10/2003

Loss Mitigation Assistant/Senior A/R Billing Specialist/Cash Application (Kelly Services)

- Ordered and reviewed loan documents such as appraisals, property titles, income documentation, bank statements, rental histories and credit reports.
- Maintained, logged, and tracked documentation for investigators.
- Daily communication with Lenders, data entry and various other duties.
- Responsible for timely and accurate data entry of all Private Mortgage Insurance Premium (PMI).
- Loaded and processed tapes up to \$5 million transmitted via electronic transfer.
- Consistently met weekly and monthly billing deadlines and also primary trainer for new employees.

### **EDUCATION**

BioWorks Certificate, Wake Tech, Raleigh, NC
Certificate, ESL/EFL Teaching, Duke University, Durham, NC
Certificate, Spanish Intermediate, Latin Immersion School, Chile/Argentina
Associate of Arts Degree, Retail Merchandising, Fashion Institute of Atlanta, Atlanta, GA

### **COMMUNITY / VOLUNTEER**

### United States Citizenship Refugee and Immigration, Raleigh, NC

**2010 – Present** 

- Volunteer ESL Teacher
- Teach reading, writing, speaking and listening skills to students eligible to apply for United States citizenship.
- Create sample citizenship tests and mock interviews to help prepare students for interview.
- 100% of my students have passed. Ages range from 30 to 71.